Petroleum Institute Records, 1958-1995
University of Houston Libraries
Petroleum Institute Records
1958-1995
University of Houston Libraries
From 1958 until 1994 the Petroleum Institute, an annual educational seminar, was held at the University of Houston. The Institute was designed to inform participants about all aspects of the petroleum industry. These records consists of brochures, evaluation results, photographs, correspondence, and program booklets.
uhapet99
2 boxes; 2 linear feet
Special Collections, University of Houston Libraries
Historical Note
The Petroleum Institute was an annual educational seminar, consisting of three courses, held at the University of Houston from 1958 until 1994. It was a joint effort between the Oil Information Committee of the Texas Mid-Continent Oil and Gas Association and the Department of Curriculum and Instruction of the College of Education. University faculty and individuals from the petroleum industry conducted the Institute. The Institute was designed to inform participants about all aspects of the petroleum industry. By doing so, it crossed the traditional course content fields normally taught at this University. The areas where the content of the Institute could be used were as follows:
1. Sciences (emphasized earth science, geology, chemistry, and physics)
2. Environmental Studies
3. Social Sciences (emphasized economics, geography, history, and political science)
The content of the courses included presentations by lecturers from the petroleum industry who were experts on a particular subject. The courses also included the development of teaching materials that could be used to infuse energy education into the curriculum. The three courses carried three semester hours of graduate credit and were accepted by many graduate programs within the Department of Curriculum and Instruction.
Scope and Contents
The collection arrived at the Archives in good order and the original order has been maintained whenever possible. The collection consists of thirty-five folders dating from 1958-1994. Materials in the collection include brochures, evaluation results, a few photographs, correspondence, and program booklets that describe the course activities. The only materials kept from the earliest years were participant rosters and programs of activities. Three years (1967-1969) were missing completely. The materials are in folders by year and arranged chronologically. The collection also included several publications relating to the oil industry, which have been filed at the end of the collection.
Acquisition
Donation, 1999
Detailed Description
- [unittitle added: see error report]
  - Roster of Participants, 1958-1966 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Programs of Activities, 1958-1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Thirteenth Petroleum Institute, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Fourteenth Petroleum Institute, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Fifteenth Petroleum Institute, 1972 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Sixteenth Petroleum Institute, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Sixteenth Petroleum Institute: Student Packet, 1973 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Seventeenth Petroleum Institute, 1974 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Eighteenth Petroleum Institute, 1975 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Nineteenth Petroleum Institute, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Twentieth Petroleum Institute, 1977 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Twenty-first Petroleum Institute, 1978 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Twenty-second Petroleum Institute, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Twenty-third Petroleum Institute, 1980 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Twenty-fourth Petroleum Institute, 1981 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Twenty-fifth Petroleum Institute, 1982 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Twenty-sixth Petroleum Institute, 1983 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Twenty-seventh Petroleum Institute, 1984 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Twenty-eighth Petroleum Institute, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Twenty-ninth Petroleum Institute, 1986 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Thirtieth Petroleum Institute, 1987 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Thirty-first Petroleum Institute, 1988 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Thirty-second Petroleum Institute, 1989 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Thirty-third Petroleum Institute, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Thirty-fourth Petroleum Institute, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Thirty-fifth Petroleum Institute, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Thirty-sixth Petroleum Institute, 1993 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Thirty-seventh Petroleum Institute, 1994 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Petroleum Institute Handouts and Letters, 1991-1995 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Publications: Oil Industry, 1961-1979 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Publications: Oil Industry (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Publications: Oil Industry (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Publications: Oil Industry (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Publications: Oil Industry (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Publications: Oil Industry (Box 2, Folder 12)